Inventory of the Great Britain, Foreign Office, Wellington House publications
Hoover Institution Archives
Great Britain, Foreign Office, Wellington House publications
1914-1918
XX230
Hoover Institution Archives
12 manuscript boxes, 5 cardfile boxes, 1 cubic foot box (8 linear feet)
Books, pamphlets, and miscellany, relating to World War I and British participation in it.
Great Britain. Foreign Office. Wellington House.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Propaganda section of the British Foreign Office.
Scope and Content of Collection
Books, pamphlets, and miscellany, relating to World War I and British participation in it. A card file index in box 18 describes this collection.
Propaganda, British.; World War, 1914-1918--Great Britain; World War, 1914-1918--Propaganda.
- "The Achievements of the Zeppelins." By a Swede. T. Fisher Unwin, London, Reprinted from the Stockholms Dagblad. 16pp. (Box 1)
- Addison, Christopher. "British Workshops and the War" T. Fisher Unwin, London. 1917. 52 pp. (Box 1)
- Addison, Chrisopher. "The Manufacture of Munitions. An Interview...to the Associated Press of the United States." Truscott, London. 1916. 8p. (Box 1)
- "Aesop's Fables up-to-date. Six prints reproduced from the original paintings by the Spanish artist Francisco Sancha." (Box 10)
- "After Three Years...A Restatement of British War Aims." Reprinted from The Round Table for September, 1917. Macmillan, London, 28pp. (Box 1)
- Airman's Outing, An. "Contace"(pseudonym). William Blackwoods, London. 1917. 323 pp. With Introduction by Major-General W.S. Brancker. (Box 1)
- Akiyama, Rear Admiral. "A Japanese view of the War." (From the Ji-Ji). T. Fisher Unwin, London. 1917. 16 pp. (Box 1)
- Appleton, W.A. "The War: A resume and a conclusion." Reprinted from Justice. 2nd Dec. 1915. 6 pp. (Box 1)
- All's Well. "Jas." London. 12pp. (Box 1)
- Alviella, Count Goblet d'. "The True and the False Pacificism." T. Fisher Unwin, London. 1917. 85 pp. (Box 1)
- "Appeal of the Belgian Workers to the Worksmen of All Nations." W. Speaight, London, 1916. 13 pp. (Box 1)
- Anderson, R. Wherry. "The Romance of Air-Fighting." Cassell, London. 1917. 24 pp. (Box 1)
- Appleton, W. A. "The Workers' Resolve." Interview with W.A. Appleton by Joseph W. Grigg. T, Fisher Unwin, London, 1917, 8 pp. (Box 1)
- Archer, William. "The Pirate's Progress." Chatto & Windus, London. 1918. 96 pp. (Box 1)
- Arsac, d', editor of "Le Soir", Brussels. "War and Peace, The German Snare." 16 pp. Hitwell, Lonndon. (Box 1)
- Asquith, H. H. "What Britain is Fighting For: A Reply to the German Chancellor." Speech....10 April, 1916. Daily Chronicle, London, 11 pp. (Box 1)
- "An Atlas of the World War." D'ngerfield Printing Co., London. 14 pp. (Box 1)
- "Austrian Terrorism in Bohemia." Czech National Alliance in Great Britain, 38 pp. (Box 1)
- Austro-Magyar Judicial Crimes. "Persecution of the Jugoslavs." Political trials, 1908-1916. The Jugoslav Committee in North America. Chicago, Ill. Printed by Hayman, Cristy & Lilly, London, 96 pp. (Box 1)
- Bailey, W. F. "The Slavs of the War Zone". Chapman & Hall, London. 1917. 266 pp. (Box 13)
- Bainville, Jacques. "Italy and the War". Traslated by Bernard Maile. Hodder & Stoughton, London. 1916. 267 pp. (Box 13)
- Balfour, A. J. "After a Year." Speech...4th August, 1915. Darling, London. 1915. 20 pp. (Box 1)
- Barker, E. "Great Britain's Reasons for Going to War." Darling, London. 1915. 10 pp. (Box 1)
- Barker, Ernest. "Linguistic Oppression in the German Empire." Longmans, Green, London. 1918. 48 pp. (Box 1)
- Barker, E. "The Relations of England and Holland." Thomas Nelson, London. 27 pp. (Box 1)
- Barry, William. "The World's Debate. A Historical Defence of the Allies". Hodder & Stoughton, London. 1917. 332 pp. (Box 13)
- Bassompierre, Albert de. "The Night of August 2-3, 1914, at the Belgian Foreign Office." Hodder & Stoughton, London. 1916. 43 pp. (Box 1)
- "The Battle Fronts of Europe." Stamford, London. 1 pp. map. (Box 1)
- Beaverbrook, Lord. "Canada in Flanders, Volume II of the Official Story of the Canadian Expeditionary Force". Hodder & Stoughton, London. 1917. 258 pp. (Box 13)
- Beck, James M. "The Case of Edith Cavell." A Study of the Rights of Non-combatants. G. P. Putmam's Sons, London. 70 pp. (Box 2)
- "The Belgian Campaigns in the Cameroons and German East Africa." Causton, London. 1917. 24 pp. (Box 2)
- Belgian Curiosities of War. No. 10 (Feb-1917). "The Free Press in occupied Belgium." Another Clandestine Newspaper in Flemish. 1 pp. (Box 2)
- The Belgian Deportations. "Facsimiles of Clandestine Leaflets in French and Flemish by Means of Which the Belgian Population Encouraged Itself to Passive Resistance in Occupied Belgium." 2 pp. Belgian Curiosities of War. No. 6. (Box 2)
- The Belgian Labour Party. (Farti Ouvrier Belge.) "Memorandum on the Peace Terms." Whitwell, London. 1917. 35 pp. (Box 2)
- Belgium. "Memorandum of the Belgian Government on the deportation and forced labour of the Belgian civil population ordered by the German Government." Barber, London. 29 pp. Le Havre, Feb.1, 1917. (see under "Memorandum") (Box 2)
- Bell, Edward Price. "The American Officers' Club in London." 11 pp. (Box 2)
- Bell, Edward Price. "The Germans and the Small Nations. An Interview with Lord French." J. J. Keliher, London. 1917. 7 pp. (Box 2)
- Benson, A. C. "The Happy Warrior. A Sight of General Smuts at Cambridge, May 1917." Reprinted from the Church Family Newspaper. University Press, Cambridge. 1917. 11 pp. (Box 2)
- Bernhardi. "A Comparative Study of the Effect of Drastic Medicine on the Expressed Opinions of General von Bernhardi." Thomas Nelson, London. 15 pp. (Box 2)
- Bevan, Edwyn. "German Social Documentary During the War." George Allen & Unwin, London. 1918. 280 pp. (Box 13)
- Bhownaggree, Mancherjee M. (Sir). "The Verdict of India." Hodder & Stoughton, London, 1916, 51 pp. (Box 2)
- Bigelow, Poultney. "An American's Opinion of British Colonial Policy." Reprinted from the New York Times. Darling, London. 1915. 8 pp. (Box 2)
- Blood and Brass. "Being Glimpses of German Psychology." T. Fisher Unwin, London. 1917. 20 pp. (Box 2)
- Blood and Treasure. "Facts and Figures of Britain's effort 1914-1917." Hayman, Christy & Lilly, London. 1918. 12 pp. (Box 2)
- Bone, Muirhead. "The Western Front" (Drawing by...).June 1917, Part I, vol. 2. Parts VII-X. June-October, 1917. # 555 (June), 650 (July); 652 (Aug); 665 (Sept), 710 (Oct). (Box 2)
- Borden, Robert (Sir). Smuts, J.C. "The Empire and the War. The Voice of the Dominions." E. P. A. Series. Empire Parliamentary Association, London. 1917. 23 pp. (Box 2)
- Borden, Robert (Sir). "The War and the Future". Hodder & Stoughton, London. 1917. 164 pp. (Box 13)
- Bourne, Cardinal. "Union Sacree. Great Britain in War Time." Burns & Oates, London, 6 pp. (Box 2)
- Bowser, Thekla. "The story of the British V. A.D. work in the Great war". Andrew Melrose, London. 300 pp. 2nd ed. (Box 13)
- Breton, Willy. "The Belgian Front and Its Notable Features." Chatto & Windus, London. 1918. 36 pp. (Box 3)
- "Britain's Great Hidden Army." R. Clay, London, n.d., 8 pp. (Box 2)
- "Britain's Mighty Efforts. Some Wonderful Scenes in One of England's Great Shell Factories." (Box 2)
- "A British Cardinal's Visit to the Western Front." and "The Universe", London. 1918. 16 pp. (Box 2)
- "British Civilian Prisoners in German East Africa. A Report by the Government Committee on the Treatment by the Enemy of British Prisoners of War." Alabaster, Passmore, London. 1918. 31 pp. (Box 2)
- "The British Empire at War. A Pictorial Souvenir of the War by Land, Sea and Air." Associated Newspapers, London, 16 pp. (Box 2)
- "British Finance and Prussian Militarism." Two Interviews. Hodder & Stoughton, London. 1917. 22 pp. (Box 2)
- "The British Labour Movement and the War." Harrison, London. 1915. 12pp. (Box 2)
- "British Medicine in the War." 1914-1917. British Medical Association, London. 1917. 138 pp. (Box 2)
- "The British Navy at War." Poster (Pictorial) (Box 2)
- "British Prisoners of War in Germany. A Statement by Mr. Tennant in the House of Commons." May 24, 1916. 1 pp. (Box 2)
- "British Universities and the War. A Record and Its Meaning." Field & Queen, London, 1917, 88 pp. (Box 2)
- "British Victory Calendar." 12 pp. (Box 2)
- "British War Aims." The Beacon, No. 1. leaflet. R. Clay, London. (Box 2)
- "The British War Pictorial London (Serial)." New Series, Vol.1, Nos. 1-3. 1917. (Box 2)
- Brunet, Emile. German calumnies. "The Anglo-Belgian Conventions." Hicks, Wilkinson & Sears. London, 23 pp. (Box 2)
- Buchan, John. "The Battle of the Somme, First Phase." Thomas Nelson, London, 109 pp. (Box 13)
- Bukowinski, M. "The Destruction of Kalisz." Reprinted from the Milwaukee Kuryer Polski. Darling, London. 1915. 12 pp. (Box 2)
- Bury, J. B. "Germany and Slavonic Civilization." Eyre & Spottiswoode, London. 1914. 16 pp. (Box 2)
- Butler, Geoffrey G. "International Law and Autocracy." A public lecture delivered before the University of Pennsylvania. Hodder & Stoughton, London. 1917. 16 pp. (Box 2)
- Cable, Boyd. "Doing Their Bit." Hodder & Stoughton, London. 1916. 134 pp. (Box 13)
- Caine, William. "Monsieur Segotin's Story." Chatto & Windus, London. 1917. 46 pp. (Box 3)
- Cairns, D. S. "Christianity and Macht-politik." War Time papers, Evangelical Information Committee, London. 20 pp. (Box 3)
- "Calendar of Culture for 1918." (Box 14)
- Campbell, Edwin. "Zeppelins. The Past and Future." The Campfield Press, St. Albans. 1918. 43 pp. (Box 3)
- Campbell, R. J. "A Letter to an American Friend." Hodder & Stoughton, London. 1918. 18 pp. (Box 3)
- "Carry On. British Women's Work in War Time." Harrison, Jehring, London. 24 pp. Pictorial. (Box 3)
- Carter, Henry. "The Control of the Drink Trade." Longmans Green, London. 1918. 323 pp. (Box 17)
- "The Case of the Allies. Being the Replies to President Wilson, and Mr. Balfour's Dispatch." Hayman, Christy & Lilly, London. 1917, 16 pp. (Box 3)
- "The Case of Naturalised British Subjects." Report of proceedings at the meeting of Naturalised British Subjects of German, Austrian, or Hungarian Birth held at Memorial Hall, Farringdon Street, London. E.C. on Thursday, 27th May, 1915. F. Eckstein, Esq. in the Chair. 22 pp. (Box 3)
- "Catholics of the British Empire and the War." Burns & Oates, London. 72 pp. (Box 4)
- Chapman, S.J. "Labour and Capital After the War". John Murray, London, 1918. 280 pp. (Box 13)
- Chesterton, G. K. "How to Help Annexation." Hayman, Christy & Lilly, London. 1918. 16 pp. (Box 3)
- Chesterton, G. K. "Lord Kitchener." London. 1917. 32 pp. (Box 3)
- Churchill, Winston; Earl Kitchener, and David Lloyd-George. "The War. Prospect and Retrospect. Report of Speeches... Nov 27th and 26th, 1914." 23 pp. (Box 3)
- "The Clandestine Publications in Occupied Belgium. Fresh Documents of Belgian Resistance in the Oppresed Country." Belgian Curiosities of War, No. 20, December, 1917. (See also "Belgian Curiosities of War.") (Box 3)
- "Civilians of Brussels Victims to German Artillery Fire." Speaight, London, 1 pp. (Box 3)
- Clifford, Dr. "Even my Pacifist Correspondents Hold That There Is Nothing Now Left For Us But To Go Forward With The War." (Portrait) (Box 3)
- Clifforf, John. "Our Fight for Belgium and What it Means." Hodder & Stoughton, London. 1918. 15 pp. (Box 3)
- Cohen, Isreal. "Anti-Semitism in Germany." Jewish Chronicle, London. 1918. 20 pp. (Box 3)
- Cohen, Isreal. "The German Attack on the Hebrew Schools in Palestine." Jewish Chronicle, London. 1918. 19 pp. (Box 3)
- Cohen, Isreal. "The Turkish Persecution of the Jews." Alabaster, Passmore, London. 1918. 20 pp. (Box 3)
- Cohn, August. "Some Aspects of the War as Viewed by Naturalized British Subjects." Council of Loyal British Subjects of German, Austrian, or Hungarian Birth, London. 1916. 24 pp. (Box 3)
- "The Collapse of German Credit." 2 pp. (Box 3)
- "The Commercial Future of Baghdad." Complete Press, London. 1917. 8 pp. (Box 3)
- "The Condition of the Belgian Workmen Now Refugees in England." T. Fisher Unwin, London. 1917. 16 pp. (Box 3)
- "The Conduct of the War by Sea." A Speech...Rt. Hon. Winston Churchill, 15th Feb., 1915. Darling, London. 1915. 24 pp. (Box 3)
- Cook, Edward T. (Sir). "The Press Censorship. (Interview) Burrup." Mathieson & Sprague. London. 1916. 12 pp. (Box 3)
- Copping, Arthur E. "Tommy's Triangle." Y.M.C.A. Hodder & Stoughton, London. 1917. 189 pp. (Box 14)
- Corbett, Julian (Sir). "The League of Nations and Freedom of the seas." Oxford University Press. 1918. 15 pp. (Box 3)
- "A 'Corpse-Conversion' Factory. A peep behind the German Lines." Darling, London. 4 pp. (Box 3)
- "Correspondence with the United States Ambassador Respecting the Execution of Miss Cavell at Brussels." Darling, London. 1915. 24 pp. (Box 3)
- Coudert, Frederic R. "British Trade Restraints and Peace Prospects." Reprint from the Public Ledger, Philadelpha, May 27th, 1916. Burrup, Mathieson, & Sprague. London. 10 pp. (Box 3)
- Cox, Harold. "The Economic Strength of Great Britain." Macmillan, London. 1914. 8 pp. (Box 3)
- "The Crimes of Germany." Field & Queen, London. 104 pp. (Box 3)
- Cromer, Earl of. "Pan Germanism." Reprinted by permission, from the Spectator of September 25th, 1915. Darling, London. 1916. 16 pp. (Box 3)
- Curtis, Lionel. "Letters to the People of India on Responsible Government." Macmillan & Co., London, 1918. 211 p. (Box 3)
- Davignon, Henri. "German Posters in Belgium. Their Value as Evidence." New texts and documents with a forword to the reader. Thomas Nelson, London. 1918. 105 pp. (Box 4)
- Dawson, A. J. "Some Battle Stories." Hodder & Stoughton, London. 1916. 239 p. (Box 4)
- "The Death of Edith Cavell." Daily News & Leader, London, Manchester. 64 pp. (Box 4)
- "The Deportaion of Women and Girls from Lille." A translated text from the note addressed by the French Government to the Governments of neutral powers on the conduct of the German authorities towards the population of the French Departments in the occupation of the enemy, with extracts from other documents.... Hodder & Stoughton, London. 1916. 81 pp. (Box 4)
- "Die Revolution in Russland" (Box 4)
- "Disclosures of a German Staff Officer." The letter of Paul Ehrhardt, merchant, soldier, and spy. With Facsimiles of his handwriting. Revised and brought up to date from the original article in "The Field" of Feburary 9 th, 1918. Field and Queen, London, 1918, 26 pp. (Box 4)
- Dixon, W. Macneile, "The Fleets Behind the Fleet. The Work of the Merchant Seamen in the War." Hodder & Stoughton, London. 132 p. (Box 14)
- Dodd, Francis. "Generals of the British Army. Portraits in Colours." Parts I & II. Country Life, London. 1917. Part I- XII Plates. Part II- XII Plates. (Box 4)
- Dodds, Elliott. "For All Prisoners and Captives. The Work of the Prisoners of War Information Bureau." Wightman, London. 12 pp. (Box 4)
- "Does the British Navy Take Prisoners?" Darling, London. 3 pp. (Box 4)
- Douglas, James. "Treasury Romances." W. Speagght, London. 1916. 15 pp. (Box 4)
- Doyle, Arthur Conan. "The German War. Some Side-lights and Reflections." Hodder & Stoughton, London, 1914, 152 p. (Box 14)
- Drysdale, A. M. "Canada to Ireland. The Visit of the 'Duchess of Connaught's Own.'" T. Fisher Unwin, London. 1917. 20 pp. (Box 4)
- Ehrhardt, Paul. "Disclosures of a German Staff Officer. The Letter of Paul Ehrhardt, Merchant, Soldier and Spy, with Facsimiles of his Handwriting." Revised and brought up to date from the original articles in The Field of Feburary 9, 1918. Field & Queen, London, 1918, 26 pp. (See under title) (Box 4)
- "The Empire and the War. Summary of Emergency Legislation Passed by the Parliaments of the Empire in Consequence of the War." Edited by Howard d' Egville, Empire Parliamentary Association. London, 101 pp. E.P.A. Series. (Box 4)
- "The Empire and the War. A Voice from India." Address by Mahrajah of Bikaner. London. 1917. 24 p. (Box 4)
- "The Fight-for-Right Pocket-Book for 1918." Darling, London, London, 1918. 84 pp. (Box 14)
- "The Fleet Annual and Naval Year Book, The Third Great War number of Twelfth Year, 1917." Published for "The Fleet" by Chapman & Hall, London, 1917. xlcv, 160, 48, 35 pp. (Box 14)
- Fisher, H.A.L. "The Value of Small States." Oxford Pamphlets, 1914, No. 17. Fifth Impression. Oxford University Press, Oxford. 25 pp. (Box 4)
- Fisher, H.A.L. "The British Share in the War" (Box 4)
- "For the Right." Essays and addresses by members of the 'Fight for Right Movement.' T. Fisher Unwin, London, 1916, 256 pp. Hardbound and paperback copies. (Box 14)
- Forsyth, P.T. "The Roots of a World Commonwealth." Hodder & Stoughton, London. 1918. 20 pp. (Box 4)
- "The Fourth of July in London." Darling, London. 11 pp. 1917 (Box 4)
- Fox, Frank. "The Battle of the Ridges. Arras, Messines, March-June, 1917." C. Arthur Pearson, London. 1918. 111 pp. (Box 14)
- French, John (Lord). "The Germans and the Small Nations. An Interview with Lord French." Keliher, London, 1917, 7 pp. By Edward Price Bell. (See under "Bell, Edward Price") (Box 4)
- "From Desk to Trench. The Making of a British Soldier." Potter, Stamford, England, 24 pp. Pictorial. (Box 4)
- "From Factory to Field. The Life Story of a British Shell." Robert & Leete, L (Box 4)
- Frost, Wesley. "Devils of the Deep." Reprinted from The Times Field and Queen, London, 8 pp. (Box 4)
- Ganga Singh (Maharajah of Bikaner). "The Empire and the War." E.P.A. Series. "A Voice from India." Empire Parliamentary Association, London, 1917, 24 pp. (Box 4)
- "The Gathering of the Nations." Reprinted from the Round Table for December, 1917. Macmillan, London, 1919. 15 pp. (Box 4)
- Gerlache de Gomerys Commdant de. "Belgium in War Time." Hodder & Stoughton, London. 1917. 243 pp. (Box 17)
- Gerlache de Gomery, Commdant de. "The Unconquerable Soul. Belgium in War Time." Hodder & Stoughton, 1918. 242 p. (Box 17)
- "German Business and German Aggression." T. Fisher Unwin, London. 1917. 23 pp. (Box 4)
- "German Catholics and Peace. A Challenge to the Centre." From The Tablet, London. 1917. 26 pp. (Box 4)
- "German Crime Calendar." 12 pp. (Box 4)
- "German Design on French Lorraine. The Secret Memorandum of the German Iron and Steel Manufacturers." George Allen & Unwin, London, 1918, 43 pp. (Box 4)
- "German Intrigues in Persia: The Diary of a German agent. The Niedermayer Expedition Through Persia to Afghanistan and India." (By W. Griesinger). Hodder & Stoughton, London, 1918. 40 pp. (See under "Griesinger, W.") (Box 4)
- "German Nationalism and the Catholic Church." With Illustrations. The Universe, London. 1917. 8 pp. (Box 4)
- "A German Naval Victory." 1 pp. (Box 4)
- "The German Note and the Reply of the Allies." T. Fisher Unwin, London. 1917. 12 pp. (Box 4)
- The German Pirate, His Method and Record." by "Ajax" (pseud.) C. Arthur Pearson, 1918. London. 120 pp. (Box 4)
- "German Prisoners in Great Britain." Tillottson, London. 62 pp. (Box 4)
- "The Germans and the Small Nations. An Interview with Lord French." Keliher, London. 1917, 7 pp. By Edward Price Bell. (See under "Bell, Edward Price") (Box 4)
- "Germany and Belgium Before and During the War." Printed for the Belgian Committee by Darling, London, 1915. 48 pp. (Box 4)
- "Germany, Turkey and Armenia. A Selection of Documentary Evidence Relating to the Armenian Atrocities from German and Other Sources." J.J. Keliher, London, 1917, 128 pp. (Box 4)
- "Germany's Fading Credit." 2 pp. (Box 4)
- "Germany's Future with a Good Peace and a Bad Peace." A Translation and Reproduction of the German Brochure: "Dutschlands zukunfut bei einem guten unt einem schlechten Frieden." Darling, London. 1918. 56 pp. (Box 4)
- "Germany's Latest Crime." (picture). "The Enslavement of Belgians." (Box 4)
- Gosling, Harry. "Peace: How to Get and Keep It." Alabaster, Passmore, London, 14 pp. (Box 5)
- Gray, Alexander. "The True Pastime. Some Observations on the German Attitude Toward the War." Methuen, London, 1915, 48 p. (Box 5)
- Gray, Alexander. "The Upright Sheaf. Germany's Intentions After the War." Methuen, London, 1915. 76 pp. (Box 5)
- Great Advance, The. "Tales from the Somme Battlefield Told by Wounded Officers and Men on Their Arrival at South-Hampton from the Front." Published by permission. Cassell, London, 183 pp. (Box 14)
- British, G. D. "East India (Constitutional Reforms)." Report on Indian Constitutional Reforms. Cd. 9109, 1918. 300 pp. (Box 5)
- Gt. Britain, G. D. Foreign Office. "An Agreement Between the British and German Governments Concerning Combatant and Civilian Prisoners of War." Miscellaneous No. 12, 1917. His Majesty's Stationery Office, 1917. Cd. 8590, 9 pp. (Box 5)
- Gt. Britain, G. D. Foreign Office. "Collected Diplomatic Documents Relating to the Outbreak of the European War." His Majesties Stationery, 1915, 561 pp. (Box 17)
- Gt. Britain, G. D. Foreign Office. "Belgium- Commission of Enquiry on the Violation of the Rules of International Law and of the Laws and Customs of War. Reports on the ..." Volume II. Reports 13 to 22 of the Commission of Enquiry. London, 191 pp. (Published on behalf of the Belgian Legation) (Box 17)
- Gt. Britain, G. D. Foreign Office. "Correspondence Respecting the European Crisis." Miscellaneous No. 6 Cd 7467. His Majesty's Stationery Office, 1914. 77 pp. (Box 5)
- Gt. Britain, G. D. Foreign Office. "Great Britain and the European Crisis. Correspondence and Statements in Parliament, Together with an Introductory Narrative of Events." His Majesty's Stationery Office, 1914, 102 pp. (Box 5)
- Gt. Britain, G. D. High Court of Justice. Probate, Divorce and Admiralty Division. "Admiralty. (In Prize) The Kim. The Alfred Nobel. The Bjornsterjne Bjornson. The Fridland. Being the Arguments in the Above Cases and the Judgement of Sir Samuel Evans." Reprinted from English Law Reports, 1915. Bradbury Agnew, London, 73 pp. (Box 5)
- Gt. Britain, G. D. War Cabinet. "Report for Year Ending December 31st, 1917." (Box 17)
- Gt. Britain, G. D. War Office. "Despatch Dated 23rd December, 1916. From General Sir Douglas Haig, G.C.B., Relating to Operations on the Western Front, Including the Battle of the Somme." His Majesty's Stationery Office, 1917, 36 pp. (Box 5)
- Great Britain, Palestine and the Jews. "Jewry's Celebration of its National Charter." Zionist Organization, London, 1918, 59 pp. (Box 5)
- Great Britain, Palestine and the Jews. "A Survey of the Christian Opinion." Zionist Organization, London, 1918, 16 pp. (Box 5)
- "The Great Parallel." Reprinted from The New York Tribune, November 2nd, 1916, Hodder & Stoughton, London. 1917. 8 pp. (Box 5)
- Gregory, Charles Noble. "Neutrality and Arms Shipments. Reprinted from the New York Herald of May 16th, 1915. Darling, London, 1915, 9 pp. (Box 5)
- Grey, Edward (Viscount). "The League of Nations." Oxford University Press, 1918. 15 pp. (Box 5)
- Grey, Edward (Sir). "Sir Edward Grey's Reply to Dr. von Bethmann-Hollweg. Being a Letter Addressed to the British Press on the 25th of August, 1915, Together with a Statement Issued by the Foreign Office on the 1st of September, 1915." T. Fisher Unwin, London, 20 pp. (Box 5)